Will Oursler Papers
Will Oursler Papers
1925-1985
Oursler, Will, 1913-1985.
43.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, journalist, novelist; pseudonyms Gale Gallagher, Nick Marino. Correspondence, research material, manuscript drafts and revisions for essays, plays, stories, novels; and published material, including articles by and about Oursler.
149442
Biographical History
Will Oursler (1913-1985) was an American author, lecturer and radio commentator. He was the son of noted novelist Fulton Oursler, and is best known for his novel N.Y. N.Y. (1954) and for his non-fiction Father Flanagan of Boys' Town (1949), which was made into a movie starring Spencer Tracy.
Oursler was born July 12, 1913, in Baltimore, Maryland, but grew up and attended schools in New York City. At first Oursler wanted to become an artist, and to that end he attended the Art Students' League in New York City. However, he decided to complete college and graduated cum laude from Harvard in 1937. After graduation, Oursler worked on the staffs of various Boston newspapers and began writing mystery novels. His first book, The Trial of Vincent Doon, was published in 1941, followed by Folio on Florence White in 1942. He also wrote under the names Gale Gallagher and Nick Marino.
World War II interrupted Oursler's career as a novelist, and he spent three years in the Pacific as a war correspondent for Fawcett Publications. He returned to writing after the war, penning numerous mystery novels and contributing articles and short stories to such well-known magazines as Collier's and Reader's Digest. Oursler also wrote non-fiction, including Father Flanagan of Boys' Town (1949, co-written with his father), Narcotics: America's Peril (1952, with Laurence Dwight Smith), The Boy Scout Story (1955), The Road to Faith (1960), The Murderers (1961, with Harry Anslinger), and Marijuana: The Facts, The Truth (1970).
Over the course of his career Oursler wrote more than 45 books including 12 mystery novels. He was vice-president of the Mystery Writers of America, a founding commodore of the Overseas Yacht Club, and president of the Overseas Press Club from 1970 to 1972. His autobiography, Family Story, was published in 1963.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Will Oursler Papers consist of three separate accessions which have not been integrated. Biographical data is filed at the beginning of the collection.
Please note that box numbers are not unique, as each series in the original accession begins again with Box 1 and both later accessions also begin again with Box 1. Please specify accession, series, and box number when requesting material to ensure retrieval of the correct items.
Original accession
This is by far the largest of the three sets of material, and contains correspondence, subject files, manuscripts, and published material.
Correspondence includes letters written to and letters written by Oursler, as well as letters of others. Much of this material was originally filed by Oursler within folders of his other materials. Where there was some quantity of these letters, they were removed with their original location on them, and placed in alphabetical order by author or recipient (if Oursler himself was the author). Where there were only one or two letters and they pertained directly to the folder of manuscripts or other material in which they were originally located, they were allowed to remain there. Thus some letters may be found in series other than the correspondence series.
Subject files contains miscellaneous personal material of Oursler's and Dr. John Myers' as well as Oursler's research materials for articles and books which he either wrote or edited. The material is filed alphabetically by type. Research materials for articles and books are filed alphabetically by the title of the work. More general research follows and is filed alphabetically by subject.
Manuscripts consists of articles, books, plays, a poem, radio and television scripts and short stories. The manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by type. Within each type the materials are arranged alphabetically by title. In cases where several titles are apparent, the manuscript was filed under what appeared to be the final or published title, and other titles for the same work were noted on the folder. Oursler had originally filed much of this material in folders. Information on these original folders was either noted on the new folder or clipped and inserted in the new folder with the manuscript. Within each work, what seemed to be the final draft was filed first, followed by earlier drafts, revisions, outlines and notes. Manuscripts of others are filed at the end of the series.
Published material includes articles about and by Oursler, published books by him (foreign editions of his works) and others, magazines and newspapers, newspaper columns by Oursler, pamphlets and reports. The materials are arranged alphabetically by type.
1967 accession
The five boxes of the 1967 accession also contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts, and published material. Correspondence includes some with radio personality John "Long John" Nebel. Subject files consists of reference material related to various of Oursler's writing projects. Manuscripts contains articles, books, pamphlets, plays, poetry, and short stories. Published material consists of articles and newspaper clippings.
1974 accession
The 1974 accession (added to the finding aid in 1978) contains correspondence and writings. Correspondence covers 1964-1974. Writings consists of articles, research material, outlines, drafts, typescripts, galleys, page proofs, and other formats. This material has received minimal processing.
Arrangement of the Collection
See Scope and Contents above. Note that the box numbers restart at Box 1 for each series in the original accession, and for each later accession; when requesting a box be sure to specify the accession and/or series to ensure retrieval of desired material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Gallagher, Gale -- Archives.; Marino, Nick, 1913-1985 -- Archives.; Oursler, Will (William Charles), 1913-1985-- Archives.; Authors, American.; Journalists -- United States.; Novelists -- American.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Galley proofs.; Manuscripts for publication.; Authors.; Journalists.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence (original accession)
  - Incoming
    - Anslinger, Harry (Box 1)
    - B (Box 1)
    - Balaber, Helen Oursler (Box 1)
    - C, E-F (Box 1)
    - Fan Mail
      - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
      - 1957 Jan-May, Oct-Nov (Box 1)
      - 1958 Feb, Mar, Jul (Box 1)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 1)
      - 1965 (Box 1)
      - 1966 January-August (Box 2)
      - Undated (Box 2)
      - Unidentified (Box 2)
    - G-H (Box 2)
    - Hardenbergh, Georgia, (Mrs. Leonard) (Box 11)
    - J-K (Box 2)
    - Kodinsky, Harry (Box 2)
    - L-M (Box 2)
    - Myers, Dr. John (Box 2)
    - Oursler, Fulton and Grace Perkins Oursler (parents) (Box 2)
    - Oursler, Mrs. Rose (Box 2)
    - Oursler, Tony (Box 2)
    - P, R (Box 2)
    - Permission letters (Box 2)
    - S-T, V-W (Box 2)
    - Worrell, Ambrose and Olga (Box 2)
    - Unidentified (Box 2)
  - To and from others
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Subject files (original accession)
  - Admission Ticket, New York Preparatory School, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Broadcast Material (Box 1)
  - Genealogical papers (Box 1)
  - Material from manuscript, N.Y., N.Y. (Box 1)
  - Myers, Dr. John (Box 1)
  - Photograph (Box 1)
  - Research material
    - Articles
      - "Boston's 'Boy Cops' Join the War on Crime" (Box 2)
      - "Conversion is a Two Way Street" (Box 2)
      - Dale Carnegie, about, unknown title (Box 2)
      - "Harvard-Government Incubator (Box 2)
      - "I Smashed California's Dope Mobsters" (Box 2)
      - Juvenile Delinquency, about, unknown title (Box 2)
      - "The New 'Evangelism'- Blessing or Blight?" (Box 2)
      - "Operation 25" (Box 2)
      - "Our Voiceless Laity" (Box 2)
      - "The Pact" (Box 3)
      - Roscoe B. Johnson Memorial Laboratory, about (Box 3)
      - "Share Our Substance!" (Box 3)
      - "Sherlock Holmes - Dead or Alive?" (Box 3)
      - "Suckers Never Learn" (Box 3)
      - UMT: Experiment in Democracy" (Box 3)
      - "The Week New York Was Poisoned" (Box 3)
    - Books
      - Family Story (Box 4)
      - Father Flanagan of Boys' Town (Box 4)
      - The Gift of Healing (Box 4)
      - Light in the Jungle
        - Halliwell Notes and Tape (Box 4)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
      - The Murderers
        - Chapters 2-5, 5 folders (Box 4)
        - Chapters 7-8, 2 folders (Box 4)
        - Chapter 9, 2 folders (Box 5)
        - Chapters 11-13, 4 folders (Box 5)
        - Chapters 16-18, 3 folders (Box 5)
        - Chapters 20-21, 2 folders (Box 5)
        - Chapters 24-26, 3 folders (Box 5)
        - Transcripts of tapes (Box 5)
    - Borg-Warner Corporation
      - Banker's Analysis, November 15, 1958 (Box 6)
      - Central Office Organization Survey (Box 6)
      - Ingersoll letters (published) (Box 6)
      - Inter-Office Memo on Farm Equipment (Box 6)
      - Industry (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
      - News Reports of Ingersoll Speech on January 19, 1942and materials on S.A. Ingersoll (Box 6)
      - Record of 60th Anniversary, Ingersoll Steel and Disc Division (Box 6)
    - "Hunter Story" (Oursler to write preface) (Box 6)
    - Oral Roberts book, material for (Box 6)
  - World War II
    - General (Box 6)
    - Notebooks (Box 6)
- Manuscripts (original accession)
  - Articles
    - "America's Lost Women" or "America's Lone Women" (Box 1)
    - "And Barrymore Said to Me" (Box 1)
    - "Are You a Revolutionary Genius?" (Box 1)
    - "Boston's 'Boy Cops' Join the War on Crime" (Box 1)
    - "The Boy Who Never Was a Scout" (Box 1)
    - "Conversion is a Two-Way Street" or "Who Said Conversion Was a One-Way Street?" or "Conversion: A Two-Way Street to God" (Box 1)
    - "Credo of a Middle Roader" (Box 1)
    - "Crime in American Cities: Los Angeles — Mr. Violence" (Box 1)
    - "Crime in American Cities: Miami — Holiday in Paradise" or "Syndicate Bonanza" (Box 1)
    - "Crime in American Cities: New Orleans — Operation Shame" or "Salesmen of Shame" or "Shame Syndicate" (Box 1)
    - "Crime in American Cities: New York — King of New York's Stolen Cars" (Box 1)
    - "Does Father Always Know Best?" (Box 1)
    - "Do Miracles Happen to You?" (Box 1)
    - "Erie's 7000 Angels" (Box 1)
    - "Faces of Faith" (Box 1)
    - "Friendship" or "Balance Your Friends" or "Do You Have the Right Friends?" (Box 1)
    - "Global Highway Hi-Signs" or "Global Road Signs Are Saving Lives" (Box 1)
    - "God Heard Me" or "He Heard My Prayer in the Depths of the Sea" (Box 1)
    - "Handicap" (Box 1)
    - "Harvard — Government Incubator" or "Harvard — Presidential Incubator" (Box 1)
    - "He Makes Paper Out of Anything" (Box 1)
    - "How Modern Are Your Manners?" (Box 1)
    - "I Smashed California's Dope Mobsters" or "I Smashed California's Dope-Car Gang" (Box 2)
    - "Kid's Country" (Box 2)
    - "Latin-World Fuehrer" or "Hitler-Castro: A Parallel" or "Cuban Red Fuehrer" or "Fuehrer Fidel" (Box 2)
    - "Magic Carpet Across International Skies" (Box 2)
    - "The Marriage Contract" or "Marriage" (Box 2)
    - "The Meaning of a Smile" (Box 2)
    - ("Murder And Two Mothers") or "Two Mothers" or "Two Mothers And a Murdered Boy" or "Two Boys, Two Mothers And a Mob" (Box 2)
    - "My Most Inspiring Moment" or "Cross in the Sand" or "Moment of Light" (Box 2)
    - "Narcotics Cartel" (Box 2)
    - "The New 'Evangelism' - Blessing or Blight?" (Box 2)
    - "New York's Flying Police" (Box 2)
    - "Operation 25" (Box 2)
    - "The Other Road" or "The Story of the Other Road" or "Why I Wrote the Boy Scout Story" (Box 2)
    - "Our Voiceless Laity" (Box 2)
    - "The Pact" or "The Sign" (Box 3)
    - "Personalities in Law Enforcement: Colonel Joseph F. Timilty" (Box 3)
    - "The Power of Silent Prayer" (Box 3)
    - "Red Sabotage" or "Anti-Sabotage Blueprint" (Box 3)
    - "Religious Therapy — Miracle or myth?" (Box 3)
    - "A Serious Report" (Box 3)
    - "Seven Secrets of Prayer" (Box 3)
    - "Share Our Substance!" (Box 3)
    - "Sherlock Holmes — Dead or Alive?" (Box 3)
    - "Ship Quiz" or "Forty Questions on Ships, The Sea, and Men Who Sail" (Box 3)
    - "So You Want to Become a Newspaperman" (Box 3)
    - "Spiritual Healing in America's Churches" (Box 3)
    - "The Strange Culture of the Hoods" or "The Mob", outlines and ideas (Box 3)
    - "Suckers Never Learn" (Box 3)
    - "They Make You Like It" (Box 4)
    - "They Preach What They Practice" (Box 4)
    - "They Sentenced Me to Die" (Box 4)
    - "This Thing Called Luck" (Box 4)
    - "Tips on a Lady's Income Tax" (Box 4)
    - "Trade Secrets of the President's Secretary" (Box 4)
    - "UNT: Experiment in Democracy" (Box 4)
    - "Village Blacksmith, 1955 Style" or "Fill 'Er Up — With Gold" (Box 4)
    - "The Week New York Was Poisoned" (Box 4)
    - "We Felt the Presence of God" (Box 4)
    - "What Do You Know About Marriage?" (Box 4)
    - "What Do You Know About Nursery Rhymes?" (Box 4)
    - "What Do You Know About Pets?" (Box 4)
    - "What Is Your Easter I.Q.?" (Box 4)
    - "What Is Your Spiritual I.Q.?" (Box 4)
    - "What Is Your Superstition I.Q.?" (Box 4)
    - "What's Your Mother Goose I.Q.?" (Box 4)
    - "Word Detective" (Box 4)
    - World War II
      - "Back Here From There" (Box 4)
      - "Battle at Point X" (Box 4)
      - "Battle of the Inkpot Generals" (Box 4)
      - "Behind Our South Pacific Lines" (Box 4)
      - "Feed 'Em While They Fight" (Box 4)
      - "For Valor Beyond Duty" (Box 4)
      - "Is War Wrecking G.I. Homes?" (Box 4)
      - "Japan Has Lost Her War" (Box 4)
      - "Jottings From A Correspondent's Notebook" (Box 4)
      - "Jungle Junkmen" (Box 4)
      - "The Last Princess" (Box 4)
      - "Philippine Return Trip" (Box 5)
      - "Report From the Pacific" (Box 5)
      - "Star Sapphire" (Box 5)
      - "Strategy of Suicide" (Box 5)
      - "These Are Our Men" (Box 5)
      - "The Wounded Are my Job" (Box 5)
    - "You Can't Go Wrong Working For Liberty" (Box 5)
    - "You're Never Shut In" (Box 5)
  - Books
    - The Apartment House
      - pp. 4-76 (Box 5)
      - Carbon copies of pp. 1-87 (Box 5)
      - Outline and preliminary material (Box 5)
      - Theme I (Box 5)
      - Theme II (Box 5)
      - Theme III (Box 5)
      - Theme IV (Box 5)
      - Theme V (Box 5)
      - Theme VI (Box 5)
      - "Minor Themes, additional people involved in the story" (Box 5)
    - As Tough As They Come (Oursler, ed.), Table of Contents, and drafts of preface (Box 5)
    - The Atheist
      - Final, pp. 1-302, 5 folders (Box 6)
      - Carbon I, pp. 1-229 B, 4 folders (Box 6)
      - Carbon II, pp. 28-285, 4 folders (Box 6)
      - Original Draft: pp. 27-263, 5 folders (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous pages and notes (Box 7)
      - Drafts, 4 folders (Box 8)
      - Notes (Box 8)
      - Outlines (Box 8)
      - Galley Proof (Box 8)
    - The Boy Scout Story
      - Final Draft opening pages, pp. 1-363 and chronology, 6 folders (Box 9)
      - Carbon, pp. 1-360 and bibliography, 5 folders (Box 9)
      - Draft Chapters 1-25, 12 folders (Box 10)
      - Galley Proofs, All Chapters, 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Caroline or The Swelling Tide (Oursler, ed.)
      - Final Draft, pp. 1-257, 4 folders (Box 11)
      - Incomplete Draft (Box 11)
      - Opening Chapters (Box 11)
      - Middle and Final Chapters (Box 11)
      - Outline (Box 11)
    - Charity or Brookhauser and God or The Tender Give
      - Incomplete Drafts I and II, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Outlines and Notes (Box 12)
    - Family Story
      - Final Draft pp. 1-368, 6 folders (Box 12)
      - Bibliography (Box 13)
      - Carbon, incomplete (pp. 177-368), 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Incomplete Drafts pp. 1-405, 3 folders (Box 13)
      - "Items for special re-check in Galleys" (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous pages and notes (Box 13)
      - Outlines (Box 13)
    - Father Flanagan of Boys' Town (with Fulton Oursler)
      - Final
        - Book One (pp. 1-45), 4 folders (Box 14)
        - Book Two (pp. 243-291), 2 folders (Box 14)
        - Book Three (pp. 292-376), 2 folders (Box 14)
        - Book Four (pp. 377-477) (Box 14)
      - Notes (Box 14)
      - Outline, pp. 1-110, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Folio On Florence White
      - Final Draft pp. 1-247, 5 folders (Box 14)
      - Duplicate or extra pages
      - Drafts, pp. 1-199, 4 folders (Box 15)
      - Drafts, pp. 200-246 (Box 16)
      - Drafts, miscellaneous pages (Box 16)
      - Notes (Box 16)
      - Outline (Box 16)
    - The Gift of Healing (Oursler, ed.)
      - Final Draft, pp. 1-261 and Chapters 17-20, 7 folders (Box 16)
      - Incomplete Draft (Box 16)
      - Extra Re-typed Pages, etc. (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 17)
      - Notes by Chapter
        - Preface (Box 17)
        - Chapters I-XX, 20 folders (Box 17)
        - Appendices and outline (Box 17)
    - The Greatest Gift on Earth (Oursler, ed.)
      - Final Drafts
        - Opening pages and Chapter I (Box 18)
        - Chapters II-XII, 11 folders (Box 18)
        - Chapters XIII-XIX, 6 folders (Box 19)
      - Drafts by Chapter
        - Preface and Chapter I (Box 19)
        - Chapters II-IX, 4 folders (Box 19)
        - Chapters XI-XXI, 3 folders (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous pages and revisions
        - I (Box 20)
        - II (Box 20)
        - Corrections by Dr. Myers (Box 20)
        - Outlines and notes (Box 20)
    - The Healing Power of Faith
      - Final pp. 1-445, 5 folders (Box 21)
      - Incomplete Draft pp. 1-387, 4 folders (Box 21)
      - Drafts, Chapters I-XXX, 13 folders (Box 22)
      - Miscellaneous pages of drafts and notes (Box 22)
    - Light in the Jungle (Oursler, ed.)
      - Forward (Box 22)
      - Drafts pp. 10-126 (Box 22)
      - Drafts pp. 94-325 (Box 23)
      - Drafts pp. 173-322 (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous pages (Box 23)
      - Outlines and Notes (Box 23)
      - Tape Transcripts
        - Preceding Pages, Reels I and II (Box 23)
        - Reels III and IV (incomplete) and Reels V-VII (Box 23)
        - Reels VIII, unnumbered Reel, and pages 1-151 (Box 23)
    - The Murderers (with Harry Anslinger)
      - Final Draft by Chapter, preface, chapters 1-28; 8 folders (Box 24)
      - Outline (Box 24)
      - Notes
        - Preface (Box 24)
        - Chapter 1, "Scope of Evil" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 2, "Case in Point" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 3, "Tenacles" and Chapter 3 A, "Tenacles" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 4, "Barons — or Butchers?" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 5 A, "Roots" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 6, "Stars in Their Eyes" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 7, "A Girl Who Died" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 8, "Lucky Likes Nice Things" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 9, "From the Mafia File" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 9 A, "The Lepke Story" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 11, "The White House Calling" (Box 24)
        - Chapter 11 A, "Hemp Around Their Necks" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 11 AA, "A Lady to Her Fingertips" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 12, "Red Chinese Lullaby" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 13, "Oozy" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 14, "A Man Named X" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 15, "A Game at Monte Carlo" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 16 A, The Addison Affair" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 17, "Dr. Jackal" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 18, "Incident at the U.N." (Box 25)
        - Chapter 20, " Mother Out-Law" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 22, "H is for Horse" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 23, "A Dog Named Kip" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 24, "For the Defense" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 25, "Pirates, Derelicts and Con-Men" (Box 25)
        - Chapter 26, "Philosophy on A Flunk" (Box 25)
    - Narcotics: America's Peril (with Lawrence Dwight Smith)
      - Final pp. 1-71, 75-295, 4 folders (Box 25)
      - Drafts
        - Chapters I-V, 3 folders (Box 25)
        - Chapters XIII-XVI (Box 25)
    - N.Y.N.Y.
      - Corrected Final Carbon pp. 1-422, 9 folders (Box 26)
      - Final Draft, 6 folders (Box 26)
      - Drafts, pp. 1-285, 8 folders (Box 27)
      - Drafts, pp. 286-351 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous pages and revision, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Notes (Box 28)
      - Outlines
        - 1. "Excerpts — Midafternoon" (Box 28)
        - 2. "Cocktail Party" (Box 28)
        - 3. "Quarrel in Beekman Place" (Box 28)
        - 4. "Crippled Boy Delivers Dress" (Box 28)
        - 5. "Maria- Polide- Basement" (Box 28)
        - 6. "Poker Game at Gottleibs" (Box 28)
        - 7. "Lights" (Box 28)
        - 8. "Episode with Girl Across Hall" (Box 28)
        - 9. "Art Student's Dance" (Box 28)
        - 10. "Excerpt- Mid-Morning" (Box 28)
        - 11. "Glendenning At Office" (Box 28)
        - 12. "Ten Seconds to Ground Floor" (Box 28)
        - 13a. "Dinner in Washington Heights" (Box 28)
        - 13. "Dinner With the Senator" (Box 28)
        - 14. "Al Burwitz In Office and After" (Box 28)
        - 15. "Signs" (Box 28)
        - 16. "Maria and Michael" (Box 28)
        - 17. "Glory and Russolinis" (Box 28)
        - 18. "Al Arranging Loan with Maurice" (Box 28)
        - 19. "Mrs. James Calding's Photographic Exhibit" (Box 28)
        - 20. "Borrowed Prostitute" (Box 28)
        - 21. "Pulpit" (Box 28)
        - 21 A. "Shopping Tour of Blanche, (Elaine) and., Selma (Box 28)
        - 22. "Ted — Theatre — Valerie" (Box 28)
        - 23. "Quarrel in Studio Apartment" (Box 28)
        - 24. "Modern Museum — V.I.P.'s" (Box 28)
        - 25. "Glendenning — Secretary-Mistress Scene" (Box 29)
        - 26. "Maurice, Sr. — In Bed With Sheila" (Box 29)
        - 26A. "Excerpts — Mid-Evening" (Box 29)
        - 27. "Taxi Ride in Park" (Box 29)
        - 28. "Ads" (empty folder) (Box 29)
        - 29. "Meeting Italian Boy and Girl" (Box 29)
        - 30. "Breakfast With the Enzio Diciddis" (Box 29)
        - 31. "Ted-Valerie — Sullivan Home" (Box 29)
        - 32. "Ten Seconds to the Lobby" (Box 29)
        - 33. "Maurice, Sr. and Lawyer in Office Downtown" (Box 29)
        - 34. "Iola and Pregnancy" (Box 29)
        - 35. "Preacher — Enzio — Family" (Box 29)
        - 36. "Zoo — Dinner — Moonlight Love Scene" (Box 29)
        - 37. "Office Luncheon" (Box 29)
        - 38. "Excerpts — Lunch" (Box 29)
        - 39. "Dinner at Lindy's and Fight in Garden" (Box 29)
        - 40. "All Night Drunk — Girl Across Hall — Calling Elaine" (Box 29)
        - 41. "Statistics" (Box 29)
        - 42. "Mrs. Silverman Attacked" (Box 29)
        - 43. "Ted — Valerie — Elopment" (Box 29)
        - 44. "Iola — Birth of the Little Girl" (Box 29)
        - 45. "Lawyer's Office Downtown" (Box 29)
        - 46. "Times Square" (Box 29)
        - 47. "Mr. and Mrs. DiCiddi, Party Prostitute" (Box 29)
        - 48. "Glory's Report" (Box 29)
        - 49. "Breakfast at the Glendennings" (Box 29)
        - 50. "Dinner at Henri's" (Box 29)
        - 51. "Windowlook" (Box 29)
        - 52. "Brief Scene in Apartment" (Box 29)
        - 53. "Maurice Raises Dough — Mama Conscious-Improving" (Box 29)
        - 54. "Ten Seconds to the Phone" (Box 29)
        - 55. "Signs Coming and Going" (Box 29)
        - 56. "The Wedding" (Box 29)
      - Draft Outlines (Box 29)
    - One Way Street
      - Draft, pp. 1-197, 5 folders (Box 29)
    - The Prudential (with Earl Chapin May)
      - Final Draft
        - Preliminary pages, proofs (Box 29)
        - pp. 1-301, 4 folders (Box 29)
        - pp. 302-490, 3 folders (Box 30)